Register to the William McBrien papers
Yale University Music Library
William McBrien papers
1995-1998
MSS 131
Yale University Music Library
5
(5 boxes)
Research materials and sound recordings pertaining to Cole Porter
McBrien, William
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The William McBrien Papers were established in the Music Library of Yale University by William McBrien in 2003.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Associated Materials
Researchers interested in Cole Porter may wish to consult MSS 82, the Cole Porter Collection at Yale, and also the Cole Porter Collection in the Music Division of the Library of Congress.
Biographical / Historical
William McBrien (1930-2009) was a professor of English at Hofstra University. He wrote biographies of Cole Porter and Stevie Smith.
Scope and Contents
William McBrien's papers pertain chiefly to Cole Porter, and arise mainly from the research for his book Cole Porter: A Biography (New York: Knopf, 1998). They include research materials, sound recordings, and other items. McBrien's original arrangement has largely been preserved, so some topics are covered in more than one series. A few items have been re-labeled or re-filed for the sake of clarity.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into five series, as follows: I. Notecards. II. Glossary of Names. III. Porter Chronology. IV. Research Topics. V. Sound Recordings.
Porter, Cole, 1891-1964
- Notecards, Series I
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of McBrien's notecards from his research on Cole Porter. Sub-series I.A is arranged alphabetically by name, and Sub-series I.B is arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - By Name, Series I.A.
    - Abbott, George (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ackeson (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Acosta, Mercedes de (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Andrews, Julie (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Astor, Brooke (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bagley, Ben (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ballard, Kay (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Barclift, Nelson (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Baz, Ben (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bentley, Andrew (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Berlin, Irving (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Branden, Sprinle (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bray, Bobby (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Brody, Elaine (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Capallo, Carmen (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Carter, Janis (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Chaplin, Saul (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Charisse, Cyd (Mrs. Tony Martin) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Columbia, David (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Conde-Nast Library (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Cooper, Lady Diana (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Cooper, Rocky (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Cora (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Coward, Noel (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Cracker, Will (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Cronin, John (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Cukor, Irene (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Cullman, Mrs. Howard (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Curtis, Tony (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Daney, Jack (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - De Menocal, Richard (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - De Mill, Agnes (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - De Wolfe, Elsie (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Duchin, Peter (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Duquette, Tony (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Eells, George (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Elg, Taina (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ewen, David (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Fairbanks, Douglas, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Farrell, Joseph N. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Fetter, Ted (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Feuer, Cy (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Fitzgerald, Ella (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Fizdale, Robert (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Fontaine, Joan (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Fox, Colin Leslie (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - French, Winsor (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Fulco di Verdura, Duke (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Gaither, Gant (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Galeska, Walter (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Galliher, John (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Garbo, Greta (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Garrett, Betty (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Gaynes, George (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Gershe, Leonard (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Gershwin, George (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Gill, Brendan (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Godowsky, Mrs. Frankie Gershwin (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Goodman, Benny (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Gray, Dolores (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Green, Stanley (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Gungbury, Barn Nicolas (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Haas, Dick (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Haas, Jean (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hadley, Bower (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hall, Fred (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hanna, Len (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Harriman, Averill (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Harris, O. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hart, Kitty Carlisle (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Haskins, James (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Havoc, Jane (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Haynes, Billy (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hepburn, Katherine (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Holm, Celeste (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Holm, Hanya (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hornblow, Mrs. Arthur (Bubbles) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Horne, Lena (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Horst (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Howard, Bart (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Howard, Jean (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hubler, Richard G. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hutchinson, Leslie (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hyde, Henry B. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Jones, Harris (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Kanin, Garson (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Kellogg, Frank (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Kelly, Ray (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Kesler, Lewis (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Kidd, Michael (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Kimball, Robert (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Kingsland, Mr. and Mrs. James (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Knef, Hildegard (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Lambert, Gamin (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Lamkin, Mr. "Speed" (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Lane, Kenneth (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Lawrence, Paula (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Lazar, Irving (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Lewine, Richard (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Liberson, Mrs. Goddard (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Logan, Joshua (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Lucinge, Jean-Lous de Faucigny (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Macintosh, Captain Alistair (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - MacLeish, Archibald (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Marbury, Elizabeth (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Martin, Ernest (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Maxwell, Elsa (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - McGlinn, John (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Merman, Ethel (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Montogomery, Bob (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Morison, Patricia (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Mountbatten, Lady Louis (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Murphy, H. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Murphy, Mrs. Donnelly (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Murphy, Senator George (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Musgrove, Stanley (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Nicholson, Charles (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - O'Brien, Kathleen (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - O'Reilly, Gretchen (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - O'Reilly, Mrs. (Niece of J. Cole) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Paley, Natasha, Princess (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Peck, Daniel (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Phillips, Michelle (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Powell, Bill (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Reilly, Charles (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Richards, Ralph (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Rochambeau, Countess de (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Rodgers, Richard (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Romanov, Mrs. Gloria (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Rosalie (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Rubinstein, Mrs. Arthur (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Rungon, Keith (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ryan, Nim (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Sarlie, Jacques (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Scheftel, Stuart (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Schenk, Joseph (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Schmitt, Louise Cole (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Schneider, Ann Kaufman (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Schwartz, Charles (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Scratin, Frank (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Shavier, Robert (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Shaw, Artie (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Short, Bobby (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Silverstein, Dr. Allen (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Siimpson, Babo (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Sirmay, Dr. Albert (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Spewack, Col. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Spewack, Sam and Bella (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Stark, Sam (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Steinert, Alex (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Stempler, Stephen (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Stevens, marti (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Sturges, Howard (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Styne, Jule (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Svetik, Gisela (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Sylvain, Paul (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Tamber, Selma (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Tee, Gerald H. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Thomas, Dr. Samuel W. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Tunney, Kieran (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Twing, Mrs. Louise (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Uppman, Theodore (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Vanderbilt, Mrs. Jean (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Venuta, Benay (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Verdon, Gwen (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Vidal, Gore (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Von Rath, Mrs. Wmm. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wallace, Loris and Joe (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Webb, J. Watson Jr. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Welch, Elizabeth (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wharton, John (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wheaton, Robert (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Whidden, Peter (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wightman, Gaylord (Janet) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wilder, Billy (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wilson, Julie (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Woolley, Monty (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - By Research Topic, Series I.B
    - 1-2-3 Club (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1943 or 44 "Thrilled to Meet Him" (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1956 Trip (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Affection (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - And the Villain Still Pursued Her (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Anti-Semitism (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Anything Goes (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Appearance (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Around the World in Eighty Days (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Art (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - ASCAP (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Beams (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Born to Dance (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Can Can -- Yale (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - China and Art (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Cigarette Case (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Cole Porter -- Scrapbook (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Cora (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Daily Life (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Death (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Deceased (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Doheny Library, USC (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Don't Fence Me In (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Du Barry Was a Lady (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Eavesdropped (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Fascinating Rhythm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Fifty Million Frenchmen, 1929-30 Scrapbook (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Food (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Fortune (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Friendships (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Gay Divorce (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Grandma Moses and Art (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Harlem (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Harvard Law School (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Haskins, James, Bricktop (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - High Society (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Hollywood (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Homosexual Affairs (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Independent Songs Written for the Armed Forces (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Indiana (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Indianapolis (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Inspiration (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Institute of the American Musical (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Jokes (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Jubilee (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Kaleidoscope (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Languages (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Late Years (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Leave It to Me (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Les Girls (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Lesbianism (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Let's Face It (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Letters (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Library (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Likes (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Lincoln Center (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - London (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Main Bocher (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Mayfair and Monmartre (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Mexican Hayride (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Mississippi Belle (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Money (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Mother (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Murder (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Museum of the City of New York (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Music (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Newspapers (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - New Yorker, The (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Night and Day (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Night Out, A (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Nymph Errant (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Openings (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Other Shows (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Out of Luck (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Out of the World (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Painting (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Panama Hattie (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Paranoia (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Paris (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Patriotism (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - PBS Telecast (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Personal Qualities (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Pirate, The (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Players Club (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Pot of Gold, A (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Publicity (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Questions for Eddy Barclift (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Red, Hot, and Blue (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Red, Hot, and Rich! An Oral History of Cole Porter (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Rehearsals (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Relatives (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Religion (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Riding Accident (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Servants (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Seven Lively Arts (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Singers (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Silk Stockings, Yale (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Smoking (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Snobbery (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Something for the Boys (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Songs (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Students (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Travels (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Trips Scrapbook (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Trunk Songs (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Venice (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Voice, Singing (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Wall to Wall Cole Porter (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - We're All Dressed Up and Don't Know Huerto Go (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Williamstown (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Within the Quota (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Women (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Yale Days (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - You'll Never Get Rich (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - You'll Never Know (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Glossary of Names, Series II
  This series contains background information on numerous people associated with Porter, arranged alphabetically.
  - Glossary of Names (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Porter Chronology, Series III
  This series contains information about Porter's life, arranged chronologically. It was originally kept in two binders. Each binder also included additional materials with no clear relationship to the chronology; these have been placed in two folders marked Miscellaneous.
  - 1890-1919 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1920-1936 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1937-1944 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1945-1950 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1953 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous (Binder 1) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1954 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1958-1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous (Binder 2) (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Research Topics, Series IV
  This series contains materials on various topics relating to Porter. It covers much of the same ground as Series I, II, and III, but Series IV has more extensive information on each topic. It appears to be McBrien's raw material, while the other Series seem to reflect his efforts to transform it into a book.
  - Acknowledgment (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Amon Papers - Script for Fred Emney (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Anything Goes (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Around the World (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Article about Porter's Student Notebooks (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Astaire, Fred (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Auden, W.H. (Box 2, Folder 30-31)
  - Balls (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Beerbohm, Max (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Berenson (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Berlin, Irving (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Biography (Box 2, Folder 36-39)
  - Can-Can (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Centennial - Cole Porter (Box 2, Folder 41-43)
  - Childhood (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Cole Porter (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Cole Porter Musical and Literary Trust (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Cole, James O. (Cole Family) (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Collins (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Corrections (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Coward, Noel (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Criticism (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Cronin, John (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Dance (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Dante (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Duke of Verdura, Fulco (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Eells, George (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Essay on Stevie Smith's Poems - Unfinished (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Family Photos / Photos of Cole Porter's Life (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Father - Samuel Fenwick Porter (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - FBI Records (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Form Letters (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Gay Divorce (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Gershwin, George (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Grandma Moses (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Grants (Box 3, Folder 65-67)
  - Hart, Moss (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Harvard (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Henry Article and other odd ends (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Hirshaw, Dorothy (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Historical (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Hollywood (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Homosexuality (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Howard, Bart (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Howard, Jean (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Illustrations (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Inquiries (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Interview with Madeline P. Smith (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Jubilee (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Kidd, Michael (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Kimball, Robert (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Kiss Me Kate (Box 3, Folder 83-85)
  - Kochno (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Krueger, Miles (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Lyrics (Box 3, Folder 88-89)
  - Maxwell, Elsa (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Menus - Cole Porter - Waldorf (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Mercer, Mabel (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Miami County Museum (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 94-95)
  - Miscellaneous Songs (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Mother (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - Murphys (Box 4, Folder 98)
  - Museum of TV and Radio (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Music Analysis (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - Musicals (History) (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - Negative Reviews (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - New Yorkers (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - Newman (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - Night and Day Film (Box 4, Folder 105)
  - Notebooks (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - Notes (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - Nymph Errant (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - Obits - Funeral (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - Oddnesses - St. John Documents and Contacts (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - Other Composers (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - Other Writings (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - Overture (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - Paris (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - Permissions (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - Peru, Indiana (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - Photographs (Box 4, Folder 118-122)
  - Porter, Linda (Box 4, Folder 123)
  - Post-Porter Material (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - Preface (Box 4, Folder 125)
  - Promotion (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - Proposal (Box 4, Folder 127)
  - Publisher (Box 4, Folder 128-129)
  - Quotes for Cole Porter Book (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - Recordings (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - Reviews (unused) (Box 5, Folder 132)
  - Reviews (Box 5, Folder 133-134)
  - Riggs, Lawrason (Box 5, Folder 135)
  - Rodgers and Hart (Box 5, Folder 136)
  - Saints / Spewack (Box 5, Folder 137)
  - Schola Cantorum (Box 5, Folder 138)
  - Seven Lively Arts (Box 5, Folder 139)
  - Shows by Porter (Box 5, Folder 140-141)
  - Smith, Madeleine (Box 5, Folder 142)
  - Songs/Tapes (Box 5, Folder 143)
  - Special Collections (Box 5, Folder 144-145)
  - Spewacks (Box 5, Folder 146)
  - Talks (Box 5, Folder 147-149)
  - Tee, Gerald (Box 5, Folder 150)
  - Teilhard de Chardin (Box 5, Folder 151)
  - Twenties (Box 5, Folder 152)
  - Venice (Box 5, Folder 153)
  - Waldorf-Astoria (Box 5, Folder 154)
  - Waugh, Evelyn (Box 5, Folder 155)
  - Welch, Elizabeth (Box 5, Folder 156)
  - Weren't We Fools? (Box 5, Folder 157)
  - Will (Box 5, Folder 158)
  - Williamstown (Box 5, Folder 159)
  - Within the Quota (Box 5, Folder 160)
  - Worcester Academy (Box 5, Folder 161)
  - Yale (Box 5, Folder 162)
  - You're the Top (Box 5, Folder 163)
- Sound Recordings, Series V
  Sound recordings have been transferred to the Historical Sound Recordings Collection in the Music Library. For further information, please contact the Curator of Historical Sound Recordings.